<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Learn on nopanicer</title>
        <link>https://nopanicer.github.io/categories/learn/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Learn on nopanicer</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>nopanicer</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nopanicer.github.io/categories/learn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>TOEFL Preparation</title>
        <link>https://nopanicer.github.io/p/toefl-preparation/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://nopanicer.github.io/p/toefl-preparation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;toefl&#34;&gt;TOEFL
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;integrated-writing&#34;&gt;Integrated Writing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;module&#34;&gt;Module
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly, concisely and accurately&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can learn from the reading that &lt;strong&gt;Reading-Fact&lt;/strong&gt;. Three theories are proposed in the reading &lt;strong&gt;Reading-point&lt;/strong&gt;, while all of them are of refuted by the lecture, which states that &lt;strong&gt;Listening-Point&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the reading claims that &lt;strong&gt;R1-theory&lt;/strong&gt;, as &lt;strong&gt;R1-reason&lt;/strong&gt;. However, the lecture does not agree with the idea and claims that &lt;strong&gt;L1-reason&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the reading indicates that &lt;strong&gt;R2-theory&lt;/strong&gt;, which is  reflected by &lt;strong&gt;R2-reason&lt;/strong&gt;. Nevertheless, the lecture counteracts the idea: &lt;strong&gt;L2-reason&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, the reading demonstrates that &lt;strong&gt;R3-reason&lt;/strong&gt;, since &lt;strong&gt;R3-reason&lt;/strong&gt;. Still, the lecture argues against such opinion-&lt;strong&gt;L3-reason&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can learn from the reading that a large, oval-shape ceramic vessel with intricate carvings was discovered in central Italy, possibly dating back to the 4th century BCE. Three theories are proposed in the reading rega rding its  purpose, while all of them are refuted by the lecture, which states that all these theories have flaw and non can be definitely proven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the reading claims that the vessel was used in religious ceremonies as the carvings on the vessel depict scenes of offering deities, possibly showing the purpose of a container for animal sacrifice to gods for blessing. However, the lecture does not agree with the idea and claims that it was common to illustrate culture narratives on everyday items, denying the religious purpose of the vessel. For example, many common items used today, such as vases and teapots, come with depictions of historical and mythical characters and events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the reading indicates that the vessel was used for storing food and drink, which is reflected in historical records and findings and suggested by the large size and sturdy construction of the vessel. Nevertheless, the lecture counteracts the idea: the intricate carvings on the vessel required great effort, and it was unlikely for people to use such an item for mundane purpose. In addition, the vessel was discovered in pristine condition, showing no wear and tear from daily handling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, the reading demonstrates that the vessel might have been used as a funerary object since similar vessels were found in other burial sites. Furthermore, the intricate carvings on the vessel are highly decorative, and they possibly represented homage to the deceased. Still, the lecture argues against such opinion- the number of this type of pottery is too small to prove wide funerary use. Besides, recent discoveries show that funerary objects in that part of Italy were almost all stone tools so the locals might have actually preferred practical items ovel symbolic ones for funerary objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;academic-discussion&#34;&gt;Academic Discussion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;question-types&#34;&gt;Question Types
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluation 40% discuss the advantage/disadvantage of one thing(whether it is good)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparison 30% dicuss the benefit/harm of two thing(which one is better)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solution 15% give a solution to some problem(a good/better answer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Argument 15% if you are approve the view, and why(whether it is right)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;topics&#34;&gt;Topics
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education 25%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work &amp;amp; Business 20%
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Profit Maximazation-Generate revenue &amp;amp; reduce costs to ensure profitablity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growth &amp;amp; Expansion-Increase market share &amp;amp; develop new market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better Products &amp;amp; Customer Satisfaction-Provide products/services better than competitors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvement &amp;amp; Innovation-Continuously improve and create new products &amp;amp; services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employee Well-being &amp;amp; Satisfaction
6 Social &amp;amp; Enviromental Responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment 15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tech 15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Urban Development 15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Economy 5%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Issues 5%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;obejective&#34;&gt;Obejective
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic: 120-180 words of relevant discussion with reasoning, example, and preferably concession&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coherence: Clear topic, flow of idea, adn connection between sentences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: Various, accurate and natural&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grammar: A mix of simple and complex sentences, preferably with atrributive clauses and participles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;structure---evaluationcomparison&#34;&gt;Structure - evaluation/comparison
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point &amp;amp; Elaboraiton + Further Elaboration + Example + Concession&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point &amp;amp; Elaboration + Further Elaboration + Seconde Point &amp;amp; Elaboration + Further Elaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point &amp;amp; Elaboration + Further Elaboration + Full Concession&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point &amp;amp; Elaboration + Further Elaboration + Sublimation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;common-points-in-educaiton&#34;&gt;Common Points in Educaiton:
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic development / Effectiveness of study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal development / Career development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teamworking and communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;training&#34;&gt;Training
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe grading shall focus on studens&amp;rsquo; efforts on assignments since we shall encourage their spirit to overcome problems rather than ignore their efforts. （我发现我经常有逻辑断点，通常需要两句或者更多句才能表达出我的想法。例如，我们要鼓励学生努力+努力才能克服困难/克服困难的品质更重要）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, effort is an important element to be considered in study and grading due to the fact that students learn from both what they have done right and what they have done wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; Which approach do you think is better: assessing students based only on their performance, or also based on their effort?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I am considered, effort is an important element to be considered in study and grading due to the fact that students learn from both what they have done right and wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate, both right and wrong experience can help student better understand knowledge. For example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, grading based on effort can help students&amp;rsquo; build their resilience, which is a vital spirit in their future life. To be more specific, those students whose efforts received affirmation will have more motivation to focus on their assignment For example, although a student get a wrong answer in the assignment, his effort has been recognized as an important part&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; What is opinion on gap year? Does it bring more advantages or disadvantages to students?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My opinion is gap year can help student find their favors and practice their ability since during this year students can try many things they are favor of and learn much from this experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate, slow down and focus on the right direction is more effective than keep going on the wrong way. Students need time to know their interests, while the gap year can give them a chance to try. For example, students who make use of this time to have a internship in business may have a better understanding of business, driving them to build a real passion in their future pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, some may claims that gap year may be a waste of time or a more expensive option to college as unversity cost is more and more expensive. However, as for the long life a person can live and the huge health one can make in his whole life, this cost is not so expensive, which means we can use this time to prepare for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; Do you think ongoing job training is the most important investment a business can make?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that ongoing job training is the most important investment a business can make based on the fact that we can not always get the perfect person but with training one can make himself the perfect person for this job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate, a person get a job doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that this person have all the properties this job needed but some central abilities, which is most valuable in the job. For example, a man who have a great intuition in market may lack the ability in data anylitical tools. Only by ongoing job training can this man better use these tools to make efficient policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is certain that ongoning job training is an essential part of business because it helps employees to stay competitive in today&amp;rsquo;s rapidly changing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be more specific, instead of relying on outdated skillsets, ongoing job trainging not only provdies employees an insight into advanced strategies but also equips them with competitive technical skills, which in turn helps the company to keep vibrant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question:&lt;/strong&gt; What is the biggest mistake that people make when it comes to the purchase of tech prodcuts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the biggest mistake people may make when they are puchasing tech products is the ignore of requirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate, one can easily diffused by the all kinds of tech products in the market, which are different in shapes, different in parameters and different in systems. Among these devices, some prodcuts are regarded as  more powerful in all aspects. However, people who ignore their turly requirement may be cheated by themselves-these products are better, but they don&amp;rsquo;t need to pruchase which means a waste of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest mistake in the purchase of tech product is that consumers almost always pay for what they do not need since people are easily misled by advertisements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate, TV and internet commericials usually illustrate the most sophisticated and powerful function of high-tech products in an exaggerated manner, which are unforunately rarely needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;opinion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic devices help students on their study&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Substantiation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, search engine on electronic devices provides many learning literature which can answer most of the students&amp;rsquo; questions, (greatly) giving them more chance to learning by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, students can find different ways of thinking for whatever questions they have with their mobile phones wherever the are, greatly broadening their mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story telling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, last week, my little niece had a homework from her biology class about animal behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of relying on limited knowledge on books, she used her mobile phone to search for diverse information on the internet, including why and how animals play, which earned her a good grade for the excellent work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opposite opinion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will lose communication skills. They shall study with classmates and teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concession&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still/Nevertheless, some may might claims / a voice arises that students could lose communication skills and they ought to study with those around them. However/Ironically, devices such as smart phones actually bring students closer to communication appications, while with proper guidance devices such as computers can significantly promote the efficency of group work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;training-1&#34;&gt;Training
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reading passage discusses the benefits of planting genetically modified trees, suggesting that these trees are hardier, provide economic advantages, and help protect wild trees from overexploitation. The lecture, however, challenges each of these points, arguing that genetically modified trees may pose significant ecological and financial challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;两种基本句式:
先说结果，再说原因
A is more likely B, since C.
直接说结果，举例论证
A is more likely B, which is showed by C
Someone claims that A, citing B
先说特征，再做因果推理
A is B, making C.
A is B, so C.
多层结果递进
A is B, so C, making/ensuring D.
这种多层级是托福写作喜欢的，不能特别多，最好就三个，其中一个从句应该短小一些，不造成阅读负担。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;也就是说读的时候要想主句，最重要的句子在哪，不是所有被修饰的都是主句。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个小 tip: 写综合写作的时候立论要(相对)更加支持 lecturer, 所以简单概括阅读观点，然后详细阐述 lecturer 观点
First, the reading claims that genetically modified trees are more likely to survive than natural trees(结论先行), citing a pest-resistant papaya in Hawaii that  prevented ringspot virus damage（ 举例补充）. In contrast(对比), the lecturer points out that genetically modified trees are genetically uniform(特征描述), making them highly vulnerable to environmental changes they were not engineered for(原因 + 结果).  Natural trees（反过来补充）, by comparison, are genetically diverse,  so at least some individuals can survive most threats, ensuring species survival.(一个两层结果递进, A is B, so C, making/ensuring D.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover(其次), the reading suggests that genetically modified trees offer economic genefits because they grow faster, yield more products and require fewer pesticides(结论先行+并列原因). The lecturer counters this (冒号说明)by highlighting associated financial burdens: farmers must pay higher prices for seeds,(两个并列原因) and legal restrictions prevent them from freely propagating the trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally(最后), the reading proposes that genetically modified trees can protect wild trees by satisfying wood demand. The lecturer argues that these trees may actually(加一个表转折) harm native species because they exhibit competitive growth patterns, competing for sunlight, soil nutrients, and water, and protentially crowding out natural trees.(感觉 gpt 逗号用的太多)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, while the reading emphasizes potential advantages, the lecture demonstrates that genetically that genetically modified trees can create serious ecological and conomic risks, calling their benefits into question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reading passage discusses the&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
